today I would like to share with you my
favorite books of all time it is not an
exaggeration to say that the books I'm
about to share with you changed my life
they changed the way I approach work how
I treat people how I see things how I
judge things how I make decisions
everything and the first book is one of
the greatest books of all time it was
written by what was one of the most
powerful men in the history of the world
he controlled the largest army in the
world could do whatever he wanted and
was infinitely Rich yet the book he
wrote is incredibly relatable even
though it has been thousands of years
since it was published you can pick it
up right now and get something useful
out of it the book is called meditations
and it was written by Marcos Aurelius a
Roman Emperor this book was never meant
to be published it is a book of notes
that Marcos wrote for himself on how to
be a good person how to live a good life
life how to control your ego how to stay
humble and how to make better choices
following the principles of the stoic
philosophy he held the highest office in
the Roman Empire the same office that
monsters like Caligula and Nero help yet
he was not corrupted by power and he is
remembered to be one of the greatest and
wisest Emperors Rome ever had he also
dealt with the death of eight of his
children people trying to assassinate
him multiple Works a pandemic and all
the stress a person can feel when trying
to run an Empire yet he took the time to
write himself notes on how to be good
and it's crazy to think that thousands
of years later we can read the thoughts
that were going to the head of one of
the greatest and wisest men of all time
even though the emperor was worshiped as
a God he knew he wasn't one so he wrote
a note to himself on things that we all
struggle with for example how hard it is
to wake up early in the morning he
writes are done when you have trouble
getting out of bed tell yourself I have
to go to work as a human being what do I
have to complain of if I am going to do
what I was born for to do the things
that I was brought into the world to do
or is this what I was created for to
huddle under the blankets and stay warm
were you born to feel nice instead of
doing things and experiencing them don't
you see the plans the birds the ants and
the spiders and bees going about their
individual tasks putting the word in
order as best they can and you are not
willing to do your job as a human being
why aren't you running to do what your
nature demands I love this quote for me
it means that we weren't built to be
comfortable our body and brain is an
incredible machine we can't grow if we
are comfortable we have to rise every
morning ready to face the day and do
what we are here for even though
smartphones were not a thing in the
Roman Empire Marcos also struggled like
we do with concentration here right
concentrate every minute like a Roman on
doing what is in front of view with
precise and genuine seriousness tenderly
willingly with Justice and referring
yourself from all other distractions do
everything as if it were the last thing
you were doing in your life and stop
being aimless stop letting your emotions
override what your mind tells you stop
being hypocritical self-centered
irritable you see how few things you
have to do to live a satisfying life if
you can manage this that's all even the
gods can ask of you there is so much
truth in this quote if we really
concentrated only on the task at hand
and nothing else imagine how far we
would go how productive we would be and
how simple life would get on worrying
about what other people think he writes
I have often wondered how is that every
man loves himself more than all the rest
of men but yet sets less value on his
own opinions of himself than on the
opinions of others how much time he
gains who does not look to see what his
neighbor says or does or think but only
as what he does himself to make it just
and Hall If any man despises me that is
his problem my only concern is not doing
or saying anything the serving of
content you always own the option of
having no opinion there is never any
need to get worked up or to trouble your
soul about things you can't control
these things are not asked to be judged
by you leave them alone on living life
fully he writes do not act as if you had
10 000 years to throw away that stands
at your elbow be good for something
while you leave and it's in your power
think of yourself as death you have
lived your life now take what's left and
leave it properly death is something the
stories meditate on a lot it is
something I also think about a lot I
even have a tattoo reminding me of it we
all act and live like we're going to
live forever which as the next book says
it's a very arrogant thing to do how do
we know we have five years more to live
or 10 or 20. we can't be sure yet we act
like we are as Seneca says life isn't
short we just waste a lot of it on being
humble which is something you wouldn't
expect a Roman Emperor to be Marcos
Aurelius writes if someone can prove me
wrong and show me my mistake in any
thought or action I shall gladly change
I seek the truth which never harmed
anyone the harm is to persist in one's
own self-deception and ignorance
meditations is a book full of quotes
that you can ponder upon and apply to
your own life it is very easy to read as
it is just a collection of notes which
means that you can open a random page on
a random day or you can read the book
over and over again and you will get
something different out of it every time
as this video is already too long I
would like to ask you to let me know in
the comments if you will be interested
in a part two of this video talking
about the other books I highly recommend
you get your hands on a copy of
meditations and I hope it is as helpful
to you as it was to me but don't rush to
finish it as is not too long but instead
read a couple of quotes every day and
reflect on them I know this kind of
video is very off topic but don't worry
next week we will be back talking about
code programming and all that stuff and
don't forget that if you want to learn
things like JavaScript python react
react native go dark flutter among many
many others for absolutely free all you
have to do is click the link below to
join any of our many free courses that
you can take right now for absolutely
free winning click the link below and I
will see you there
see you on the next one bye
thank you
[Music]